[
	{
		"answerText": "cogito ergo sum [or I am thinking, therefore I am; prompt on the cogito][10] This French dualist philosopher who wrote Discourse on Method declared cogito ergo sum. He questioned the veracity of our senses with scenarios involving melting wax and an evil demon.",
		"prompts": [
			"cogito",
			"10",
			"This",
			"French",
			"dualist",
			"philosopher",
			"who",
			"wrote",
			"Discourse",
			"Method",
			"declared",
			"cogito",
			"ergo",
			"sum",
			"He",
			"questioned",
			"veracity",
			"our",
			"senses",
			"with",
			"scenarios",
			"involving",
			"melting",
			"wax",
			"and",
			"an",
			"evil",
			"demon"
		],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2014 | 04 | 1 | Philosophy | None | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Nietzsche and Kierkegaard criticized this proposition because its first statement presupposes self-existence. For 10 points each:  [10] Identify this proposition concluding self-existence that for one philosopher, serves as the basis for all further knowledge. It was reached by indirect proof after a process of hyperbolic doubt in Discourse on Method. ",
		"answers": [
			"cogito",
			"ergo",
			"sum",
			"I",
			"am",
			"thinking",
			"therefore"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "the Leviathan[10] The Leviathan is a political structure imagined by this English philosopher, who warned that the alternative is a state of nature where life is \"solitary, poor, nasty, brutish, and short\".",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2014 | 05 | 16 | Philosophy | None | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This entity is depicted wielding both a sword and a papal staff with a body made of people. For 10 points each: [10] Identify this symbol of the Commonwealth, headed by a Sovereign with civil and ecclesiastical power. It represents a covenant where people cede their natural rights for a state of peace. ",
		"answers": [
			"the",
			"Leviathan",
			"10",
			"The",
			"political",
			"structure",
			"imagined",
			"by",
			"this",
			"English",
			"philosopher",
			"who",
			"warned",
			"that",
			"alternative",
			"state",
			"nature",
			"where",
			"life",
			"solitary",
			"poor",
			"nasty",
			"brutish",
			"and",
			"short"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "anarchy[10] Thucydides fictionalized a dialogue between realist Athens and this idealist island during the Peloponnesian War. This island refuses to surrender to the Athenians, who justify its destruction wih \"might makes right\".",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2014 | 06 | 12 | Philosophy | None | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: For 10 points each, identify the following about realism in international relations. [10] Realists believe that the international system is characterized by this property, since it lacks a universal central authority. Because of this, uncertainty and self-help pervade the system.",
		"answers": [
			"anarchy",
			"10",
			"Thucydides",
			"fictionalized",
			"dialogue",
			"between",
			"realist",
			"Athens",
			"and",
			"this",
			"idealist",
			"island",
			"during",
			"Peloponnesian",
			"War",
			"This",
			"refuses",
			"to",
			"surrender",
			"Athenians",
			"who",
			"justify",
			"its",
			"destruction",
			"wih",
			"might",
			"makes",
			"right"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "being [or Sein][10] Martin Heidegger, the author of Being and Time, was a forerunner of this movement most notably espoused by Jacques Derrida in Of Grammatology. This form of criticism believes that there is \"nothing outside the text.\"",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "BISB |2013 | 2 | 10 | Philosophy | None | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This phenomenon occurs \"toward-death\" and \"in-the-world\", and one form of it is defined as \"this entity which each of us is himself.\" For 10 points each [10] Name this central concept of dasein (pr. DIE-ZIN). This word is paired with \"time\" in the title of a 1927 work of philosophy.",
		"answers": [
			"being",
			"Sein",
			"10",
			"Martin",
			"Heidegger",
			"author",
			"Being",
			"and",
			"Time",
			"was",
			"forerunner",
			"this",
			"movement",
			"most"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "syllogism[10] In order to get the upper hand, your partner remarks, \"Well, you've got a terrible sense of taste, and you have big feet.\" Such irrelevant, personal attacks, are often described by this two-word Latin phrase.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Brookwood Invitational Scholars Bowl |2013 | 1 | 8 | Philosophy | None | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: You are arguing that all M&Ms don't have the same flavor with a terrible arguer who thinks they do. For 10 points each: [10] Your adversary claims, \"All M&Ms are made of chocolate, and all chocolate has the same flavor, therefore all M&Ms have the same flavor\"--an example of these three-part statements first described by Aristotle.",
		"answers": [
			"syllogism",
			"10",
			"In",
			"order",
			"to",
			"get",
			"upper",
			"hand",
			"your",
			"partner",
			"remarks",
			"Well",
			"you've",
			"got",
			"terrible",
			"sense",
			"taste",
			"and",
			"you",
			"have",
			"big",
			"feet",
			"Such",
			"irrelevant",
			"personal",
			"attacks",
			"are",
			"often",
			"described",
			"by",
			"this",
			"two-word",
			"Latin",
			"phrase"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "The Birth of Tragedy from the Spirit of Music [accept Die Geburt der Tragödie aus dem Geiste der Musik][10] This work by the same author of The Birth of Tragedy first introduced the concept of the Übermensch, which is described as the ultimate goal for humanity.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "GSAC |2013 | 1 | 18 | Philosophy | None | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This work was later reissued by its author with an additional preface, An Attempt at Self-Criticism. For 10 points each: [10] Name this work which contrasts the Apollonian and Dionysian interpretations of a certain art form.",
		"answers": [
			"The",
			"Birth",
			"Tragedy",
			"from",
			"Spirit",
			"Music",
			"Die",
			"Geburt",
			"der",
			"Tragödie",
			"aus",
			"dem",
			"Geiste",
			"Musik",
			"10",
			"This",
			"work",
			"by",
			"same",
			"author",
			"first",
			"introduced",
			"concept",
			"Übermensch",
			"which",
			"described",
			"as",
			"ultimate",
			"goal",
			"for",
			"humanity"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Immanuel Kant[10] This philosopher gave a critique of Kant in the work Kant and the Problem of Metaphysics. This Nazi supporter proposed the concept of Dasein, or \"existence,\" in Being and Time.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "GSAC |2013 | 5 | 18 | Philosophy | None | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This philosopher encouraged others to \"dare to know\" in his work \"What is Enlightenment?\" For 10 points each: [10] Name this German philosopher who examined a priori knowledge in his Critique of Pure Reason.",
		"answers": [
			"Immanuel",
			"Kant",
			"10",
			"This",
			"philosopher",
			"gave",
			"critique",
			"in",
			"work",
			"and",
			"Problem",
			"Metaphysics",
			"Nazi",
			"supporter",
			"proposed",
			"concept",
			"Dasein",
			"existence",
			"Being",
			"Time"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Karl Heinrich Marx[10] Marx is known for this multi-volume treatise, which posits that the tendency of the rate of profit to fall leads to the exploitation of labor by employers to produce the title asset.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "GSAC |2013 | 6 | 5 | Philosophy | None | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This man claimed that \"[s]ociety does not consist of individuals, but expresses the sum of interrelations, the relations within which these individuals stand.\" For 10 points each: [10] Name this man, whose writings inspired the theory of historical materialism.",
		"answers": [
			"Karl",
			"Heinrich",
			"Marx",
			"10",
			"known",
			"for",
			"this",
			"multi-volume",
			"treatise",
			"which",
			"posits",
			"that",
			"tendency",
			"rate",
			"profit",
			"to",
			"fall",
			"leads",
			"exploitation",
			"labor",
			"by",
			"employers",
			"produce",
			"title",
			"asset"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Principia Mathematica[10] This British thinker wrote Principia Mathematica along with Alfred Whitehead; other works by him include \"A History of Western Philosophy\" and \"Why I am not a Christian.\"",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "GSAC |2013 | 7 | 12 | Philosophy | None | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This work attempted to derive a set of axioms that could be used to prove mathematical truths. For 10 points each: [10] Name this work of set theory and mathematical logic that was shown to have failed to fulfill its goal by Gödel's Incompleteness Theorems. ",
		"answers": [
			"Principia",
			"Mathematica",
			"10",
			"This",
			"British",
			"thinker",
			"wrote",
			"along",
			"with",
			"Alfred",
			"Whitehead",
			"other",
			"works",
			"by",
			"him",
			"include",
			"A",
			"History",
			"Western",
			"Philosophy",
			"and",
			"Why",
			"I",
			"am"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Friedrich Nietzsche[10] In The Birth of Tragedy Nietzsche compares the more chaotic art of Dionysus to the art of this god, which is guided more by reason.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 6 | 20 | Philosophy | None | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: His book Ecce Homo contains chapters titled \"Why I Am So Wise\" and \"Why I Am a Destiny.\" For 10 points each: [10] Name this German philosopher who said \"God is dead\" and related concepts like the ubermensch in his book Thus Spake Zarathustra.",
		"answers": [
			"Friedrich",
			"Nietzsche",
			"10",
			"In",
			"The",
			"Birth",
			"Tragedy",
			"compares",
			"more",
			"chaotic",
			"art",
			"Dionysus",
			"to",
			"this",
			"god",
			"which",
			"guided",
			"by",
			"reason"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Confucianism (accept word forms including Confucius)[10] This collection of Confucius's sayings was compiled by his followers, and includes his descriptions of concepts such as the Golden Rule.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 8 | 9 | Philosophy | None | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Mencius was one member of this school of thought. For 10 points each: [10] Name this philosophy formulated by a namesake Chinese philosopher which advocates filial piety. It was the state philosophy of the Han dynasty.",
		"answers": [
			"Confucianism",
			"word",
			"forms",
			"including",
			"Confucius",
			"10",
			"This",
			"collection",
			"Confucius's",
			"sayings",
			"was",
			"compiled",
			"by",
			"his",
			"followers",
			"and",
			"includes",
			"descriptions",
			"concepts",
			"such",
			"as",
			"Golden",
			"Rule"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Mohism [or Mojia][10] The Mohist theory of \"impartial care\" is often translated as the \"Universal\" type of this emotion, which is discussed drunkenly in Plato's Symposium.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "PACE |2013 | 3 | 5 | Philosophy | None | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  This school sought objective moral standards called fa, and followed ten doctrines such as \"Thrift in Funerals\" which were laid out in ten triads of essays. For 10 points each:  [10] Name this Chinese school of thought which was opposed to Confucianism for its lack of concern with filial piety. It was wiped out by Legalism. ",
		"answers": [
			"Mohism",
			"Mojia",
			"10",
			"The",
			"Mohist",
			"theory",
			"impartial",
			"care",
			"often",
			"translated",
			"as",
			"Universal",
			"type",
			"this",
			"emotion",
			"which",
			"discussed",
			"drunkenly",
			"in",
			"Plato's",
			"Symposium"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Baruch Spinoza[10]  Spinoza's monism contrasts with this theory that asserts that the mind is an independently existing but non-physical substance. It was developed by Rene Descartes.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round01.docx | 4 | Philosophy |  | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This philosopher approached the mind-body problem with the assertion that everything that exists, including human beings, is a \"mode\" of God, a theory that he espoused in his work Ethics.",
		"answers": [
			"Baruch",
			"Spinoza",
			"10",
			"Spinoza's",
			"monism",
			"contrasts",
			"with",
			"this",
			"theory",
			"that",
			"asserts",
			"mind",
			"an",
			"independently",
			"existing",
			"but",
			"non-physical",
			"substance",
			"It",
			"was",
			"developed",
			"by",
			"Rene",
			"Descartes"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "pragmatism[10]  This author of The Principles of Psychology and \"The Will to Believe\" sought a middle ground between \"tough-minded\" and \"tender-minded\" philosophers in his work Pragmatism.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round02.docx | 1 | Philosophy |  | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this school of philosophy that emphasizes practical utility and uses actual value to define truth. It was espoused by John Dewey and the author of \"How to Make Our Ideas Clear\", C.S. Peirce (\"purse\").",
		"answers": [
			"pragmatism",
			"10",
			"This",
			"author",
			"The",
			"Principles",
			"Psychology",
			"and",
			"Will",
			"to",
			"Believe",
			"sought",
			"middle",
			"ground",
			"between",
			"tough-minded",
			"tender-minded",
			"philosophers",
			"in",
			"his",
			"work",
			"Pragmatism"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "relativism[10]  This Greek sophist was an early relativist. His teachings are described in Theaetetus and his namesake Platonic dialogue, where he discussed if virtue can be taught. He famously stated \"man is the measure of all things\".",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round04.docx | 1 | Philosophy |  | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This concept states that there is no absolute truth or validity, but that truth should be viewed within the reference frame of a language or culture. The \"moral\" type of this concept is particularly contentious.",
		"answers": [
			"relativism",
			"10",
			"This",
			"Greek",
			"sophist",
			"was",
			"an",
			"early",
			"relativist",
			"His",
			"teachings",
			"are",
			"described",
			"in",
			"Theaetetus",
			"and",
			"his",
			"namesake",
			"Platonic",
			"dialogue",
			"where",
			"he",
			"discussed",
			"if",
			"virtue",
			"can",
			"be",
			"taught",
			"He",
			"famously",
			"stated",
			"man",
			"measure",
			"all",
			"things"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "separation of powers [prompt on \"tripartite system\"][10]  This French Enlightenment political philosopher articulated a theory of the separation of powers. He argued that monarchies relied on the principle of virtue, and despotisms relied on fear.",
		"prompts": [
			"tripartite",
			"system",
			"10",
			"This",
			"French",
			"Enlightenment",
			"political",
			"philosopher",
			"articulated",
			"theory",
			"separation",
			"powers",
			"He",
			"argued",
			"that",
			"monarchies",
			"relied",
			"principle",
			"virtue",
			"and",
			"despotisms",
			"relied",
			"fear"
		],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round06.docx | 12 | Philosophy |  | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This model proposes the division of the state into independent branches, each no more powerful than the others. This system often yields legislative, judicial, and executive branches.",
		"answers": [
			"separation",
			"powers"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Epicureanism[10]  This Roman Epicurean stated that the \"nature of mind and soul\" is \"corporeal\" in his De rerum natura, or \"On the Nature of Things\", which also asserts that nothing exists except bodies and the void.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round08.docx | 11 | Philosophy |  | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this philosophical school, named after its Athenian founder, which believed pleasure to be the ultimate good, advocating moderate asceticism in order to be free from pain.",
		"answers": [
			"Epicureanism",
			"10",
			"This",
			"Roman",
			"Epicurean",
			"stated",
			"that",
			"nature",
			"mind",
			"and",
			"soul",
			"corporeal",
			"in",
			"his",
			"De",
			"rerum",
			"natura",
			"On",
			"Nature",
			"Things",
			"which",
			"also",
			"asserts"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "\"On Denoting\"[10]  This writer of \"Why I am Not a Christian\" and \"On Denoting\" is also known for his namesake paradox, which pertains to a set of all sets that does not include itself.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round12.docx | 18 | Philosophy |  | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this essay that attempts to tackle the problems of substitutivity, the excluded middle, and negative existentials by introducing a theory of definite descriptions.",
		"answers": [
			"On"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Summa Theologica [or Summation of Theology; prompt on \"Summa\"][10]  This Scholastic philosopher defended Christianity and put forth a four-part definition of faith in Summa con Gentiles, which he expanded on in Summa Theologica.",
		"prompts": [
			"Summa",
			"10",
			"This",
			"Scholastic",
			"philosopher",
			"defended",
			"Christianity",
			"and",
			"put",
			"forth",
			"four-part",
			"definition",
			"faith",
			"in",
			"Summa",
			"con",
			"Gentiles",
			"which",
			"he",
			"expanded",
			"in",
			"Summa",
			"Theologica"
		],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round13.docx | 5 | Philosophy |  | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this incomplete work structured as a series of objections and responses. It contains five arguments for the existence of God.",
		"answers": [
			"Summa",
			"Theologica",
			"Summation",
			"Theology"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "principle of sufficient reason[10]  This philosopher used the principle of sufficient reason to argue that the reason for this world is that it is the best of all possible worlds in Monadology.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round14.docx | 20 | Philosophy |  | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this principle which states that all truths must have a cause.",
		"answers": [
			"principle",
			"sufficient",
			"reason",
			"10",
			"This",
			"philosopher",
			"used",
			"to",
			"argue",
			"that",
			"for",
			"this",
			"world",
			"best",
			"all",
			"possible",
			"worlds",
			"in",
			"Monadology"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Martin Heidegger[10]  This Heidegger work discusses viewing objects as a means to an end as being \"ready-to-hand\", as opposed to \"present-at-hand\". Heidegger never finished this work, so the part on the second title concept is incomplete.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round15.docx | 21 | Philosophy |  | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this post-Kantian German philosopher, who argued that experience was grounded in intentionality and care. He coined the term Dasein to refer to a state of being that understands itself through its own existence.",
		"answers": [
			"Martin",
			"Heidegger",
			"10",
			"This",
			"work",
			"discusses",
			"viewing",
			"objects",
			"as",
			"means",
			"to",
			"an",
			"end",
			"being",
			"ready-to-hand",
			"opposed",
			"present-at-hand",
			"never",
			"finished",
			"this",
			"so",
			"part",
			"second",
			"title",
			"concept",
			"incomplete"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "arithmetic (or Arithmetik)[10]  This man had earlier analyzed the statement 7+5=12 in his Critique of Pure Reason. The most well-known formulation of his categorical imperative states that one should only do something if it should be done universally.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round02.docx | 18 | Philosophy |  | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Identify this discipline, the foundations of which were written about by Gottlob Frege. That work attacks the notion that 7+5=12 is a synthetic statement.",
		"answers": [
			"arithmetic",
			"Arithmetik",
			"10",
			"This",
			"man",
			"had",
			"earlier",
			"analyzed",
			"statement",
			"7+5=12",
			"in",
			"his",
			"Critique",
			"Pure",
			"Reason",
			"The",
			"most",
			"well-known",
			"formulation",
			"categorical",
			"imperative",
			"states",
			"that",
			"one",
			"should",
			"only",
			"something",
			"if",
			"be",
			"done",
			"universally"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Answer: Soren Kierkegaard (accept Anti-Climacus, John the Silent, or Johannes de Silentio)[10]  Some consider Kierkegaard to be the first philosopher from this movement, which claimed that the individual must be the starting point of philosophy. Other members of it included Simone de Beauvoir and Martin Heidegger.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round04.docx | 9 | Philosophy |  | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this Danish philosopher, author of The Sickness Unto Death and Fear and Trembling.",
		"answers": [
			"Answer:",
			"Soren",
			"Kierkegaard",
			"Anti-Climacus",
			"John",
			"Silent",
			"Johannes",
			"de",
			"Silentio",
			"10",
			"Some",
			"consider",
			"to",
			"be",
			"first",
			"philosopher",
			"from",
			"this",
			"movement",
			"which",
			"claimed",
			"that",
			"individual",
			"must",
			"starting",
			"point",
			"philosophy",
			"Other",
			"members",
			"included",
			"Simone",
			"Beauvoir",
			"and",
			"Martin",
			"Heidegger"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "John Rawls[10]  Rawls described this concept as a combination of liberty and equality in a work titled [this] as Fairness. His A Theory of [this] was refuted by Robert Nozick in Anarchy, State, and Utopia, and it's sometimes also defined as \"giving each his due\".",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round06.docx | 6 | Philosophy |  | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this American philosopher whose \"original position\" parallels the \"state of nature\". He argued that inequalities in society should benefit the least advantaged, his \"difference principle\".",
		"answers": [
			"John",
			"Rawls",
			"10",
			"described",
			"this",
			"concept",
			"as",
			"combination",
			"liberty",
			"and",
			"equality",
			"in",
			"work",
			"titled",
			"Fairness",
			"His",
			"A",
			"Theory",
			"was",
			"refuted",
			"by",
			"Robert",
			"Nozick",
			"Anarchy",
			"State",
			"Utopia",
			"it's",
			"sometimes",
			"also",
			"defined",
			"giving",
			"each",
			"his",
			"due"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Being and Time (or Sein und Zeit)[10]  This German philosopher  joined the Nazi party soon after writing Being and Time. His other works include Kant and the Problem of Metaphysics and On the Way to Language.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round08.docx | 4 | Philosophy |  | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this philosophical work, which uses phenomenological ontology to analyze the concept of Dasein, which describes the awareness of human consciousness.",
		"answers": [
			"Being",
			"and",
			"Time",
			"Sein",
			"und",
			"Zeit",
			"10",
			"This",
			"German",
			"philosopher",
			"joined",
			"Nazi",
			"party",
			"soon",
			"after",
			"writing",
			"His",
			"other",
			"works",
			"include",
			"Kant",
			"Problem",
			"Metaphysics",
			"On",
			"Way",
			"to",
			"Language"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Tractatus Logico-Philosophicus[10]  This Austrian philosopher wrote Tractatus Logico-Philosophicus and described the \"beetle in a box\" thought experiment in his posthumously published Philosophical Investigations.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round10.docx | 21 | Philosophy |  | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this philosophical work comprised of seven propositions, such as \"the world is everything that is the case\" and \"whereof one cannot speak, thereof one must be silent.\"",
		"answers": [
			"Tractatus",
			"Logico-Philosophicus",
			"10",
			"This",
			"Austrian",
			"philosopher",
			"wrote",
			"and",
			"described",
			"beetle",
			"in",
			"box",
			"thought",
			"experiment",
			"his",
			"posthumously",
			"published",
			"Philosophical",
			"Investigations"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Stoicism (accept word forms)[10]  This founder of Stoicism rejected the cynicism of his teacher, Crates of Thebes. He declined Athenian citizenship in order to remain faithful to his native Citium.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round12.docx | 19 | Philosophy |  | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this Hellenistic school of philosophy which advocated for self-control to think clearly. Its members included Marcus Aurelius, Cicero, and Seneca the Younger.",
		"answers": [
			"Stoicism",
			"word",
			"forms",
			"10",
			"This",
			"founder",
			"rejected",
			"cynicism",
			"his",
			"teacher",
			"Crates",
			"Thebes",
			"He",
			"declined",
			"Athenian",
			"citizenship",
			"in",
			"order",
			"to",
			"remain",
			"faithful",
			"native",
			"Citium"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "John Stuart Mill[10]  Along with Jeremy Bentham, Mill is known as a proponent of this ethical theory, which maintains that the moral course of action is the one which results in the greatest good for the greatest number.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round14.docx | 5 | Philosophy |  | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this English philosopher whose feminist ideas were published in \"The Subjection of Women\". He described his \"harm principle\" in On Liberty.",
		"answers": [
			"John",
			"Stuart",
			"Mill",
			"10",
			"Along",
			"with",
			"Jeremy",
			"Bentham",
			"known",
			"as",
			"proponent",
			"this",
			"ethical",
			"theory",
			"which",
			"maintains",
			"that",
			"moral",
			"course",
			"action",
			"one",
			"results",
			"in",
			"greatest",
			"good",
			"for",
			"number"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "skepticism[10]  This Spanish-American philosopher discussed the title concept \"in religion\" and \"in common sense\" in The Sense of Beauty and wrote Scepticism and Animal Faith as well as The Life of Reason.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round16.docx | 4 | Philosophy |  | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this philosophical school of thought which sought ataraxia, or \"freedom from worry\", and argued against absolute certainty in belief. One philosopher refuted it in a work titled [this] and Animal Faith.",
		"answers": [
			"skepticism",
			"10",
			"This",
			"Spanish-American",
			"philosopher",
			"discussed",
			"title",
			"concept",
			"in",
			"religion",
			"and",
			"common",
			"sense",
			"The",
			"Sense",
			"Beauty",
			"wrote",
			"Scepticism",
			"Animal",
			"Faith",
			"as",
			"well",
			"Life",
			"Reason"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Leviathan[10]  This English philosopher and social contract theorist wrote that life in the state of nature was \"nasty, brutish, and short\" in  Leviathan. He also argued that an effective government must have absolute authority.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round16.docx | 22 | Philosophy |  | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this work which describes life without a central government as a \"war of all against all\". Its \"Of Man\" section describes the fear of violent death as the greatest evil.",
		"answers": [
			"Leviathan",
			"10",
			"This",
			"English",
			"philosopher",
			"and",
			"social",
			"contract",
			"theorist",
			"wrote",
			"that",
			"life",
			"in",
			"state",
			"nature",
			"was",
			"nasty",
			"brutish",
			"short",
			"He",
			"also",
			"argued",
			"an",
			"effective",
			"government",
			"must",
			"have",
			"absolute",
			"authority"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Immanuel Kant[10] Kant introduced this term that refers to the subjective experience of noumena. Kant claimed that knowledge was limited to these appearances of things, which are the only directly observable objects.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2012 | 5 | 6 | Philosophy | None | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: He cited Horace's \"Sapere Aude\" as part of the transition out of immaturity in What is Enlightenment? For 10 points each:  [10] Name this philosopher who concluded that metaphysics is inherently dialectical in his Critique of Pure Reason. He also wrote the Critique of Judgment and the Metaphysics of Morals.",
		"answers": [
			"Immanuel",
			"Kant",
			"10",
			"introduced",
			"this",
			"term",
			"that",
			"refers",
			"to",
			"subjective",
			"experience",
			"noumena",
			"claimed",
			"knowledge",
			"was",
			"limited",
			"these",
			"appearances",
			"things",
			"which",
			"are",
			"only",
			"directly",
			"observable",
			"objects"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Zeno[10] Another philosopher, Zeno of Citium, founded this school of philosophy, whose adherents included Epictetus and the Roman Emperor Marcus Aurelius. It proposed that virtue was the only good.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "BHSAT |2011 | 1 | 19 | Philosophy | None | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Answer the following questions about Classical philosophers, for 10 points each. [10] One philosopher of this name from Elea was a student of Parmenides, and according to a Platonic dialogue, debated a young Socrates. His paradoxes of motion feature the motionless arrow and Achilles racing a tortoise.",
		"answers": [
			"Zeno",
			"10"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "time[10] Martin Heidegger later joined the Nazis, whose central philosophy came from this anti-Semitic autobiography presaging Germany's invasion of Russia, written by an imprisoned Adolf Hitler.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "BHSAT |2011 | 2 | 2 | Philosophy | None | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Immanuel Kant's transcendental aesthetic defines this as the a priori ability to perceive oneself, and Bergson contrasted this concept with \"free will.\" For 10 points each: [10] Name this concept central to  a Martin Heidegger work that developed the concept of Dasein, in which it is contrasted with \"Being\".",
		"answers": [
			"time",
			"10",
			"Martin",
			"Heidegger",
			"later",
			"joined",
			"Nazis",
			"whose",
			"central",
			"philosophy",
			"came",
			"from",
			"this",
			"anti-Semitic",
			"autobiography",
			"presaging",
			"Germany's",
			"invasion",
			"Russia",
			"written",
			"by",
			"an",
			"imprisoned",
			"Adolf",
			"Hitler"
		]
	}
]